{"name": "70R", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. In the figure shown below, the triangles are similar with \u25b3ABC \u25b3RST.  The lengths of 3 sides are given, in inches. What is the length of side RT, in inches ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "1", "C": "", "D": "3", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. At the same time Thao begins counting aloud backward from 100 by 2's. Takeisha begins counting aloud forward from 15 by 3's. If they count in unison, what number will they say at the same time ?", "choices": {"A": "17", "B": "34", "C": "36", "D": "51", "E": "66"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. A television that normally sells for $260.00 is reduced in price by 15%. What is the reduced price of the television ?", "choices": {"A": "$221.00", "B": "$245.00", "C": "$258.00", "D": "$275.00", "E": "$299.00"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. If a = -2, then 5a\u00b3 = \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "40", "B": "30", "C": "-30", "D": "-40", "E": "-1000"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. For all a and b, 12a\u00b2 + 7ab - 10b\u00b2 = ?", "choices": {"A": "(6a - 2b)(2a + 5b)", "B": "(3a + 2b)(4a - 5b)", "C": "(3a - 2b)(4a + 5b)", "D": "(2a - 2b)(6a + 5b)", "E": "(2a - b)(6a + 10b)"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. Which expression, when added to 2x\u00b2 + 2x, gives a result of x ?", "choices": {"A": "-2x\u00b2 + x", "B": "-2x\u00b2 - x", "C": "-x\u00b2 - x", "D": "2x\u00b2 - x", "E": "-x"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. In a certain high school, exactly 4 out of every 15 students are in the high school band. If 300 students go to the high school, how many are in the band ?", "choices": {"A": "20", "B": "24", "C": "60", "D": "75", "E": "80"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. A triangle has an interior angle measuring 123\u00b0. Which of the following CANNOT be the measure of another of the triangle\u2019s interior angles ?", "choices": {"A": "1\u00b0", "B": "23\u00b0", "C": "30\u00b0", "D": "45\u00b0", "E": "60\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. The price and demand for a company's product are related by the equation p(q + 4) = 400, where p is the price per unit, in dollars, and q is the number of units the company is able to sell. How many units can the company sell if their price per unit is $10.00 ?", "choices": {"A": "36", "B": "40", "C": "44", "D": "360", "E": "386"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. What is the average of -1, 0, and 2 ?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "1", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. Tia and Tom, working together, stuffed 960 envelopes. Tia stuffed twice as many as Tom did. How many envelopes did Tom stuff?", "choices": {"A": "240", "B": "320", "C": "480", "D": "640", "E": "720"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. In a softball league,  of the pitchers are left-handed and the rest are right-handed. What percentage of the pitchers in the league are right-handed ?", "choices": {"A": "20%", "B": "40%", "C": "50%", "D": "80%", "E": "95%"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. How many integers between 1 and 100 are divisible by 3, with zero remainder?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "30", "C": "33", "D": "66", "E": "99"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. (x + 1)(x - 1)(x + 2) is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "x + 2", "B": "3x + 2", "C": "x3 - 2", "D": "x3 + 2x2 + x + 2", "E": "x3 + 2x2 - x - 2"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. Which of the following is a graph of 1 \uff1c x \uff1c 2 \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. For all a \u2260 0\uff0cthe expression  simplifies to: ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. Support beams AC and BD are each 15 feet long in the rectangular storage shed shown below (top view). If the shed is 9 feet wide along AD, how many feet deep is it along AB ?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "9", "C": "12", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. What is the area of the figure shown below, in square centimeters?(Note: All angles are right angles and the lengths are given in centimeters.)", "choices": {"A": "82", "B": "176", "C": "266", "D": "473", "E": "621"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. What is the value of the expression y3 - x2 + xy when x = 2 and y = -3 ?", "choices": {"A": "17", "B": "-17", "C": "-25", "D": "-29", "E": "-37"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. What is the solution statement for the inequality -8(x - 4) &lt; -24 ?", "choices": {"A": "x &lt; -12", "B": "x &lt; -7", "C": "x &lt; -1", "D": "x &lt; 1", "E": "x \uff1e 7"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. The absolute value equation |x - 4| = 7 has how many real solutions?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "1", "C": "2", "D": "3", "E": "4"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. If 3x+3 = 1 , the x = \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "-3", "B": "-2", "C": "-1", "D": "0", "E": "1"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. In the right triangle shown below, what is the length of AB, in meters?", "choices": {"A": "20", "B": "", "C": "10", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. Aaron has a summer job laying sod. The sod comes in rolls that cover a rectangular strip 1 meter wide and 10 meters long. How many rolls are needed to cover a flat rectangular lawn that is 27 meters wide and 100 meters long?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "27", "C": "100", "D": "270", "E": "2,700"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. For a certain square, the square's perimeter, in feet, is numerically equal to the square's area, in square feet. How many feet long is one side of the square?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "4", "D": "8", "E": "16"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. When the line 2x - 3y = 5 is graphed in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, what is its slope?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "2", "E": "5"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. When asked his age, the algebra teacher said, \u201cIf you square my age, then subtract 26 times my age, the result is 56\u201c. How old is he?", "choices": {"A": "26", "B": "28", "C": "30", "D": "52", "E": "56"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Two mutually tangent circles are inscribed in a rectangle as shown below. What is the area of the portion of the figure shown shaded, in square inches?", "choices": {"A": "32 - 4\u03c0", "B": "32 - 8\u03c0", "C": "32 - 16\u03c0", "D": "32 - 32\u03c0", "E": "32 - 64\u03c0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, a circle with a radius of 1 coordinate unit is centered at (1,1). At what point does this circle touch the x-axis?", "choices": {"A": "\uff08-1, 0\uff09", "B": "(0, 0)", "C": "(0, 1)", "D": "(1, 0)", "E": "(1, 1)"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. Three lines are graphed in the standard (x, y)  plane. In the entire plane, there are only 2 points where any of the lines intersect another. Which of the following must be true about the lines?", "choices": {"A": "Two of the lines are perpendicular.", "B": "Two of the lines are parallel.", "C": "The lines form an equilateral triangle.", "D": "Exactly 1 of the lines goes through the origin.", "E": "Two of the lines go through the origin."}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. A car used 32 gallons of gasoline for a 660-mile trip. Among the following, which is the closest approximation of the car's miles-per-gallon ratio for this trip?", "choices": {"A": "20", "B": "21", "C": "26", "D": "32", "E": "48"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. Because (31,323)2 = 981,130,329  then 981,130,328 factors as:", "choices": {"A": "(31,323 - 1)2", "B": "(31,323 + 1)2", "C": "(31,323)(31,323 + 1)", "D": "(31,323)(31,323 - 1)", "E": "(31,323 + 1)(31,323 - 1)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. The average of a set of 4 numbers is 5. If one of the 4 numbers is 2, what is the average of the other 3 numbers?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "3", "D": "", "E": "6"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. In the right triangle shown below, how many inches long is MP ?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "10", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. Which of the following is an equation for the line graphed in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Each of the 6 faces of a certain cube has an area of 1 square inch. What is the volume of this cube, in cubic inches?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "3", "C": "6", "D": "12", "E": "18"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. What is the largest possible product for 2 even integers whose sum is 30 ?", "choices": {"A": "56", "B": "60", "C": "104", "D": "200", "E": "224"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. For all x such that sin x \u2260 0 and cos x \u2260 0,  simplifies to \uff1a", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. At a distance of 100 feet from the base of a tree on level ground, a forester measures the angle from the ground to the tree top to be 53\u00b0, as shown below. What is the tree's height, in feet?", "choices": {"A": "100 sin 53\u00b0", "B": "100 cos 53\u00b0", "C": "100 tan 53\u00b0", "D": "100 cot 53\u00b0", "E": "100 sec 53\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. Which of the following is an expression for the area of the triangle shown below?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. Lengths of the sides of the trapezoid shown below are given in inches. What is the area of the trapezoid, in square inches?", "choices": {"A": "32", "B": "48", "C": "72", "D": "80", "E": "96"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. If n is an integer, and , what is the greatest possible value for n ?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "4", "C": "5", "D": "6", "E": "7"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. Apartment numbers are needed for the doors of a new apartment complex. Each single digit from 0 through 9  costs $0.10. What is the total cost for all the single digits needed to number the doors from l through 30 ?", "choices": {"A": "$3.00", "B": "$5.00", "C": "$5.10", "D": "$7.50", "E": "$30.00"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. Use the following information to answer questions 44-46. Three online coffee companies offer different shipping rates to their customers for coffee shipments. Brewer's charges a flat rate of 1 dollar per pound of coffee shipped. WebCuppa charges 2 dollars per shipment plus 50 cents per pound of coffee shipped. World of Jo charges one amount for any shipment, as illustrated in the graph below.44. Which of the following statements about the shipping rates is true?", "choices": {"A": "Brewer's charges less than WebCuppa to ship any amount of coffee less than w pounds.", "B": "Brewer's charges more than WebCuppa to ship any amount of coffee less than w pounds.", "C": "Brewer's charges more than WebCuppa to ship any amount of coffee.", "D": "WebCuppa charges more than World of Jo to ship any amount of coffee.", "E": "World of Jo charges more than the other 2 companies to ship any amount of coffee."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. Use the following information to answer questions 44-46. Three online coffee companies offer different shipping rates to their customers for coffee shipments. Brewer's charges a flat rate of 1 dollar per pound of coffee shipped. WebCuppa charges 2 dollars per shipment plus 50 cents per pound of coffee shipped. World of Jo charges one amount for any shipment, as illustrated in the graph below.45. To determine the weight of coffee, w pounds, for which Brewer's and WebCuppa charge the same amount to ship, you could solve which of the following equations?", "choices": {"A": "1.00 = 2.00 + 0.50w", "B": "1.00w = 2.00 + 0.50", "C": "1.00w = 2.00 + 0.50w", "D": "1.00w = 2.00w + 0.50", "E": "1.00w + 0.50 = 2.00"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. Use the following information to answer questions 44-46. Three online coffee companies offer different shipping rates to their customers for coffee shipments. Brewer's charges a flat rate of 1 dollar per pound of coffee shipped. WebCuppa charges 2 dollars per shipment plus 50 cents per pound of coffee shipped. World of Jo charges one amount for any shipment, as illustrated in the graph below.46. WebCuppa provides the following table showing that Brewer\u2019s and World of Jo each charge $5.00 to ship 5 pounds of coffee, while WebCuppa charges only $4.50 to ship 5 pounds of coffee.Which of the following table entires shows corresponding charges for shipping 10 pounds of coffee?", "choices": {"A": "weight of coffee                      Charge, by company     (pounds)                   Brewer's     WebCuppa      World of Jo              10                           $10.00           $9.00              $10.00", "B": "weight of coffee                      Charge, by company     (pounds)                   Brewer's     WebCuppa      World of Jo             10                           $10.00           $7.00              $10.00", "C": "weight of coffee                      Charge, by company     (pounds)                   Brewer's     WebCuppa      World of Jo             10                           $10.00           $7.00              $5.00", "D": "weight of coffee                      Charge, by company     (pounds)                   Brewer's     WebCuppa      World of Jo             10                           $10.00           $9.00              $5.00", "E": "weight of coffee                      Charge, by company     (pounds)                   Brewer's     WebCuppa      World of Jo             10                           $5.00           $4.50              $5.00"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below, point P is  the center of the circle and has coordinates (6, 9). Point Q on the circle has coordinates (9, 13). What is the circle's radius, in coordinate units?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "4", "C": "5", "D": "6", "E": "7"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. Point C is the center of the circle shown below. If minor arc  is 8 inches long and the circle's circumference is 20 inches, what is the measure of \u2220DCE?", "choices": {"A": "102\u00b0", "B": "104\u00b0", "C": "120\u00b0", "D": "144\u00b0", "E": "152\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. In the right triangle below, if , what is the value of  ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. A fruit bowl contains 8 pears, 15 peaches, and 2 oranges. A piece of fruit is selected at random from the bowl. What is the probability that the fruit is NOT a peach?", "choices": {"A": "0.08", "B": "0.32", "C": "0.40", "D": "0.60", "E": "0.67"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, the vertices of a triangle are at(-3, -1), (2, 1), and (0, 4). Which one of the following points is inside the triangle?", "choices": {"A": "(2, 2)", "B": "(1, 3)", "C": "(0, 0)", "D": "(-1, 4)", "E": "(-2, 0)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. For what value of b does the equation x2 + 12x + b = 0 have only one real solution for x ?", "choices": {"A": " 0", "B": " 6", "C": " 12", "D": "24", "E": " 36"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. If |x - 2| &gt; 4, at which of the 5 labeled points could x be located on the real number line below ?", "choices": {"A": "A", "B": "B", "C": " C", "D": "D", "E": "E"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. Alicia is learning to bowl. Her scores for the first 10 games she bowled were 78, 63, 92, 95, 88, 86, 85, 73, 90, and 85.What is the median of these 10 bowling scores?", "choices": {"A": "83.5", "B": "85", "C": "85.5", "D": "87", "E": "88"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. Whenever a &lt; b, then |a - b| is equivalent to: ", "choices": {"A": "a - b ", "B": "-a + b", "C": "-a - b", "D": "|a| - |b|", "E": "|b| - |a|"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. A right triangle, \u25b3ABD, has lengths measured in units as shown in the figure below. How many units long is BD ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. The vertices of \u25b3ABC are indicated below in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane. Which of the following equations determines the line containing side AB ?", "choices": {"A": "-3y - 4x = -1", "B": "y - 4x = -7", "C": "y - 4x = -22", "D": "y - 4x = 13", "E": "4y - x = 22"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. What is the period of the function y = sin 4x ?(Note: The period of y = sin x is 2\u03c0\uff09", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. Mary holds 2 part-time jobs each of which pays her a regular hourly wage. One day she worked 4 hours driving her cab and then spent 3 hours delivering packages. She earned $75 in wages for the day. A week later, she drove her cab 2 hours and delivered packages for 6 hours, earning $78 in wages. How much money does she earn per hour for delivering packages?", "choices": {"A": "$12.00", "B": "$10.70", "C": "$10.20", "D": "$9.75", "E": "$9.00"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. For all x \u2265 0 ,  = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}]}